Guide to the Martin Wong Papers ca. 1982-1999 MSS.102
Fales Library and Special Collections
Martin Wong Papers
ca. 1982-1999
Fales Library and Special Collections
Wong, Martin
MSS.102
29.5 Linear Feet (33 boxes)
Born Martin Victor Wong in Portland, Oregon on July 11, 1946, Wong was raised by his Chinese-American parents in San Francisco. Wong was involved in performance art in the 1970's, but focused almost exclusively on painting after moving to New York in the early 1980's. The self-taught Wong, whose work showed a distinct gay sensibility, became a respected, renowned and prolific painter in New York's downtown art scene. He also cultivated both working and personal relationships with graffiti artists and enthusiasts in that scene. His compositions combine gritty social documents, cosmic witticisms, and symbolic languages that chronicle survival in his drug-and-crime-besieged Lower East Side neighborhood. In addition to his painting, Wong also experimented with poetry and prose, much of which he recorded on long paper scrolls. Wong died of AIDS in 1999.
Provenance
The Martin Wong Papers were donated by the estate of Martin Wong, overseen by Mrs. Benjamin (Florence) Wong Fie and assisted by Wendy Olsoff and Peter Broda, in December 1999 and January 2000. Most of the materials in the collection were retrieved from Wong's Lower East Side apartment; additional documents were donated by Mrs. Wong Fie from her personal papers.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Biographical Note
Martin Wong is known for his paintings of gritty cityscapes, including New York's Chinatown and Lower East Side, and for championing graffiti a legitimate art form in the 1980's and 1990's. Wong was a respected and prolific painter in New York's downtown art scene in the 1980's. In addition, Wong cultivated both working and personal relationships with graffiti artists and enthusiasts.
Born Martin Victor Wong (although he sometimes playfully lists himself as "Martin Genghis Wong") in Portland, OR, on July 11, 1946, Wong was raised by his Chinese-American parents in San Francisco. He graduated from George Washington High School in 1964. Wong was involved in performance art in the 1970's, but focused almost exclusively on painting after moving to New York in the early 1980's.
In addition to his painting, Wong experimented with poetry and prose, much of which he recorded on long paper scrolls. Highly anecdotal and semi-autobiographical, Wong's writing features an exuberant and fanciful stream-of-consciousness style.
Fascinated by New York's renegade graffiti artists, Wong befriended such spray-can virtuosos as "Daze" (Chris Ellis), "Lee," "Laroc," and "LA2," among others. Wong forged a particularly strong and enduring friendship with Daze, and helped publicize his work, as well as the work of other graffiti artists, in exhibitions and through the Museum of American Graffiti. This grassroots institution was devised to showcase the vibrant panoply of contemporary graffiti art.
Wong's circle also included arts journalist Theresa Herron, Steve Hernandez, "Magic Sam," artist John Ahearn, "Lady" Joyce Ryan, Barry Blinderman, and Wendy Olsoff and Penny Pilkington of the PPOW gallery. Also significant in Wong's life were his mother, Mrs. Benjamin Wong Fie, and his "Aunt Nora" (a.k.a. Aunt Ellie), Eleanora Tam. In artistic terms, one of Wong's most significant relationships was that shared with poet and playwright Miguel Pinero, whom Wong met in 1982. Affectionately referred to by Wong as both "Mikey" and "Mickey," Pinero was considered "Loisaida's reigning outlaw poet" (Sweet Oblivion, 35). A some-time roommate of Wong's, Pinero collaborated with Wong on such paintings as "Attorney Street Handball Court" (1982-84) and "Little Got Rained On" (1983). Pinero's text was incorporated into the paintings such that Wong's imagery serves as evocative illustration. Pinero also appears not infrequently in Wong's paintings as subject - "Portrait of Pinero" (1982), "Penitentiary Fox" (1988), "La Vida" (1988) - where he is typically depicted reading or writing.
In the span of a decade, Wong achieved considerable recognition and success, with a formidable arsenal of solo and group exhibitions to his credit. Wong is most closely associated with downtown galleries Semaphore, Exit Art, and PPOW, but his work has also appeared at such venues as the Metropolitan Museum of Art, the New Museum of Contemporary Art, and the New York Historical Society. Wong died in 1999, after a protracted battle with AIDS.
Sources/Related Material:
The Clones of Bruce Lee [videorecording]: the art of Martin Wong. (New York: Pow Wow Productions, 1995)
Martin Wong [videorecording]. (New York: Pow Wow Productions, c1998)
Sweet Oblivion: the urban landscape of Martin Wong. (New York: Rizzoli Books, c1998)
Scope and Content Note
The Martin Wong Papers are a part of the Downtown Collection at the Fales Library, New York University. The Fales Library is the primary special collections division of the NYU libraries, housing nearly 200,000 volumes of English and American literature from 1700 to the present. Strengths of the collection include the development of the English and American novel, with an emphasis on the Gothic and the Victorian novel. The Downtown Collection, of which the Martin Wong Papers are a part, is a comprehensive collection of printed materials, archives, and other materials related to the Downtown New York scene from ca. 1975 to the present.
The Martin Wong Papers are comprised of over 100 sketches and drawings, more than 30 sketchbooks, correspondence, poetry and prose, biographical documents, source material, audio and videocassette recordings, photos, and graffiti tag-books, graffiti-related materials and parts of Wong's personal library.
Source material includes magazines, postcards, posters, memorabilia, and a vast collection of Wong's snapshots. Biographical material features Wong's curriculum vitae, copies of newspaper and magazine profiles of Wong, business cards and addresses of associates, and publicity materials related to Wong's exhibitions. Wong's poetry and prose contains a significant portion of the biographical material - much of it anecdotal in tone. The graffiti portion of the archive is comprehensive and includes sketchbooks, illustrations, text on graffiti (authored by both Wong and others), publicity material pertaining to graffiti exhibitions, and materials pertaining to the graffiti film: "Wild Style." Of particular interest are the numerous examples of tagging found in both the sketchbooks and other artwork.
A zealous collector and graffiti enthusiast, Wong amassed a considerable cache of graffiti material in the 1980's. The Martin Wong Papers also document New York's downtown arts scene in the 1980's and 1990's, with particular emphasis on Wong's participation and recognition in the gallery scene.
SERIES DESCRIPTION
Series I: Correspondence contains a box of documents ordered alphabetically by correspondent's last name (in most cases). Where surnames or complete names were missing, first names or nicknames were used. The series contains letters, postcards, holiday and greeting cards, and memos of both a personal and business nature.
Series II: Artwork (sketches, drawings, sketchbooks) is comprised of 2 boxes of artwork plus additional oversize material. Because of missing chronological or titular information, the files are ordered in random order.
Missing Title
Subseries A contains a box of Wong's artwork, including sketches, drawings, and sketchbooks.
Subseries B contains a box of art by other people, among them John Ahearn and Mark Kostabi (copies only). Two portraits of Wong are also included.
Series III: Source Material is by far the largest series, and is comprised of approximately 4 boxes of imagery (not including oversize) inspirational to Wong. Magazines, posters, invitations to gallery events and parties, memorabilia, and graffiti materials comprise the series. Where possible, the series has been ordered alphabetically by theme - themes include boxing, prisons, firefighters, Chinatown, and sign language.
Series IV: Biographical contains 1 box of material related to Wong's life and personal history, and additional oversize material. The series includes Wong's curriculum vitae, artist profiles, a copy of Wong's birth certificate and high school reunion program, and his poetry and prose.
Series V: Audio and Videocassettes is comprised of one box containing 3 videocassette recordings and an audiocassette. Topics include Wong's "Chinatown" paintings and NEA funding.
Series VI: Photos is comprised of hundreds of snapshots, most of which constitute source material for Wong's art. The series is ordered by theme: photos of Wong, photos of Wong's work, and source photos of people, cityscapes and urban life, cars and motorbikes, men in uniform, works of art and museum pieces, birds and beasts, Chinatown and Chinese imagery, and various miscellaneous source snapshots.
Series VII: Personal Library consists of nearly one hundred books from Wong's own personal collection, many of which served as source material for Wong's trademark images - firefighters, constellations, sign language, prison, and Chinatown, among others. Three items in this series also include drawings by Wong and by Daze on the inside cover; these items are marked with an asterisk. The series is comprised of 4 boxes.
Series VIII: Albums consists of a photo album of the opening of the Museum of American Graffiti containing clippings, ephemera, and photographs of the museum and the opening celebration. A number of photographs include identification labels created by Wong of individuals at the event, including a number of graffiti artists.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading and chronologically depending on the nature of the series. Oversized material, while included in the number sequence of the series is separated into oversized boxes.
The files are grouped into 7 series.
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Artwork
Series III [A]: Catalogs, Graffiti, Invites, Posters, Source Material, etc.
Series III [B]: Asian-Language Source Material
Series IV: Biographical
Series V: Video & Audiocassettes
Series VI: Photography
Series VII: Personal Library
Oversize - Series II: Artwork
Oversize - Series III
Oversize - Series IV: Biographical
Accretion 2009 - Series VIII: Albums
Related Material at the Fales Library and Special Collections
Fashion Moda Archive (MSS.091)
Separated Material
There is no record of materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Sketchbooks.; Artists and community -- United States; New York (N.Y.).; Manuscripts for publication.; Avant-garde (Aesthetics); Photographs.; Posters.; Clippings (information artifacts); Handscrolls.; Painting, American |z New York (State)|z New York.; East Village (New York, N.Y.); Drawings; Audiotapes.; Videocassettes.; Postcards.; Urban issues.; Social conditions |x Art |z United States |y 20th century.; Art and society -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Figurative art, American -- 20th century.; Painting, American |y 20th century.; Poetry.; Art, Modern -- 20th century; Art, American -- New York (State) -- New York.; Correspondence.; Books.; Downtown writers.; Graffiti.; Wong, Martin; Daze; Herron, Annie; Ahearn, John, 1951-
- Series I: Correspondence, 128504
  - ABC No Rio, undated; 128570 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Act Up/New York, undated; 128569 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aegis Networking Inc, undated; 128568 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ahearn, undated; 128567 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alliance for Asian American Arts and Culture, undated; 128566 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Andres, undated; 128565 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Asian American Arts Center, undated; 128564 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Barrett, Sam, undated; 128563 (Box 1, Folder 7a.)
  - Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, undated; 128562 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Broken Rifles of the War Resisters League, undated; 128561 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Byrne, David/Talking Heads, undated; 128560 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chalk & Vermilion Fine Arts, undated; 128559 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chinatown History Project, undated; 128558 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Circle Fine Art Corporation, undated; 128557 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Community Prescription Services, undated; 128556 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cutting, Jennifer McGregor, undated; 128555 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Daze (Ellis, Chris), undated; 128554 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Drexler, Rosalyn, undated; 128553 (Box 1, Folder 16a)
  - Dzine, 144036 (Box 1, Folder 16b)
  - Fashion Institute of Technology, undated; 128552 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fire Dep't, City of NY, undated; 128551 (Box 1, Folder 17a.)
  - Flushing Council on Culture & the Arts, undated; 128550 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Gabor, Lauren, undated; 128549 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Gavin, Jen, undated; 128548 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Godzilla/Asian American Arts Network, undated; 128547 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Groninger Museum, undated; 128546 (Box 1, Folder 21a.)
  - Hernandez, Steve, undated; 128545 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Herron, Theresa (Zamodia, Theresa; Herron, Annie), undated; 128544 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hiller, Kam Ping, undated; 128543 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Human Resources Admin. Medical Assistance Program, undated; 128542 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Islip Art Museum, undated; 128541 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Jan, Janet (cousin), undated; 128540 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Jim (nephew-?), undated; 128539 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Jon Gerstad Gallery, undated; 128538 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Kim, Elaine (U.C. Berkeley), undated; 128537 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center/Center Stage, undated; 128536 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Magic Sam/"Sami Magic", undated; 128535 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - McDougal, Littell, & Company, undated; 128534 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Needham, Peter, undated; 128533 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Oberlin College, Dep't. of Art, undated; 128532 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Ordover, Jerald (attorney), undated; 128531 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Ortiz, Angel, undated; 128530 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Pace Gallery, undated; 128529 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Philippe Briet, Inc, undated; 128528 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - P.P.O.W. (Pilkington, Penny and Olsoff, Wendy), undated; 128527 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Public Art Fund, undated; 128526 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - The Queen's Museum, undated; 128525 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Real Art Ways, undated; 128524 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Repo History, undated; 128523 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Richardson, Charles, undated; 128522 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Rowberry, John W./"The Alternate", undated; 128521 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Ryan, Lady Joyce, undated; 128520 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Sebren, Sam, undated; 128519 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Skipitares, Theodora, undated; 128518 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Snug Harbor Cultural Center, undated; 128517 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Sotheby's, undated; 128516 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Swenters, Veerle, undated; 128515 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Tam, Eleanora (Aunt Nora/Aunt Ellie), undated; 128514 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - UNICEF, undated; 128513 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum, undated; 128512 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - White Columns, undated; 128511 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, undated; 128510 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Who's Who in American Art, undated; 128509 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Wolfe, Brian, undated; 128508 (Box 1, Folder 58a.)
  - Wong, Martin, undated; 128507 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Wong Fie, Mr. And Mrs. Benjamin (parents), undated; 128506 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Various: Postcards, Holiday Cards, Notes, Letters, undated; 128505 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Series II: Artwork, 128374
  - Subseries A: Art by Wong and Wong's Sketchbooks, 128385
    - Sketchbook, undated; 128503 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sketchbook [Datamark Writing Tablet], undated; 128502 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sketchbook [Mead Composition Book], undated; 128501 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Sketchbook [Black Bound Book], undated; 128500 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Sketchbook [Without Cover], undated; 128499 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sketchbook, undated; 128498 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Sketchbook [Strathmore Drawing Notebook 3], undated; 128497 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Sketchbook [Spring Compositions Book], undated; 128496 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Sketchbook [Pen-Tab Composition Book], undated; 128495 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Sketchbook, undated; 128494 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Sketchbook, undated; 128493 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Sketchbook, undated; 128492 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Sketchbook [Strathmore Drawing Notebook 1], undated; 128491 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Sketchbook [Strathmore 400 Drawing Notebook], undated; 128490 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Mini-Sketchbook with Chinatown Sketches, undated; 128489 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Mini-Sketchbook with Sign Language Sketches, undated; 128488 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Mini-Sketchbooks, undated; 128487 (Box 1, Folder 17A)
    - Mini-Sketchbooks [Black Attica 2], 273563 (Box 1, Folder 17B)
    - Mini-Sketchbooks [Orange Memo Book], 273564 (Box 1, Folder 17C)
    - Sketchbook, undated; 128486 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Sketchbook, undated; 128485 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Sketchbook [Strathmore Drawing Notebook 2], undated; 128484 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Sketchbook, undated; 128483 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Sketchbook, undated; 128482 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Sketchbook (incl. sketches by Daryl Triviera), undated; 128481 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Sketchbook [Bound Brown Book], undated; 128480 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Drawing: "Magic Sam," Feb 15 1985, 128479 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Drawing: "Ana Pena", undated; 128478 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Drawing: "Bella," April 8 1994, 128477 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Drawing: Marie Antoinette studies, w/ text, undated; 128476 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Drawing: carrots, w/text, undated; 128475 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Drawing: bathroom studies, undated; 128474 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Drawing: "God Dog Holy Fool," b/w sketch of a head, undated; 128473 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Sketch: man's face (self-portrait?), b/w pen & ink sketches, undated; 128472 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Transparency: "Yield" (in sign language), undated; 128471 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Sketch: Wong's apartment, viewed through window, undated; 128470 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Drawing: chess game, undated; 128469 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Sketch: figure study, b/w seated man (reading?), undated; 128468 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Drawing: bunny crowd, undated; 128467 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Sketches: "Winner Take All/Hotcha Gotcha", undated; 128466 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Sketches: frame and panel, w/text (project plan?), undated; 128465 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Sketches: Asian figures, undated; 128464 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Drawing: "Hip Hop", undated; 128463 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Sketch: "Museum of American Graffiti", undated; 128462 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Drawings: assorted character heads, undated; 128461 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Drawings: Egyptian museum pieces (series), undated; 128460 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Drawing: boots, undated; 128459 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Sketch: sad face, undated; 128458 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Sketch: shopfront grillwork, undated; 128457 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Drawing: man reading, undated; 128456 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Drawing: woman in cowboy hat, undated; 128455 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Drawing: "Free Willy", undated; 128454 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Drawing: seated figures, undated; 128453 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Drawing: "Semaphore", undated; 128452 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Drawing: luggage, undated; 128451 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Drawing: household items, undated; 128450 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Drawing: sign language series, undated; 128449 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Sketches: Chinatown series, undated; 128448 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Sketch: interior w/ open doors, undated; 128447 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Drawings: archaic Chinese script, undated; 128446 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Sketches: cityscapes, undated; 128445 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Drawing: Chinese garden, undated; 128444 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Sketches: eastern statuary series, undated; 128443 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Sketch: man w/gaping mouth, undated; 128442 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Sketch: pointing hand, w/text fragment, undated; 128441 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Sketch: man's tattooed back, undated; 128440 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Drawings: studies for "My Self-Portrait", undated; 128439 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Sketch: figure studies, undated; 128438 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Drawing: head of a woman w/ pink hair, undated; 128437 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Drawing: large breasts, undated; 128436 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Drawing: little green man w/ graffiti tags, undated; 128435 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Drawings: animation characters, undated; 128434 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Drawing: man w/ big cigar, undated; 128433 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Sketch: "Martin Wong Chinatown USA", undated; 128432 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Drawing: 2-door car, undated; 128431 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Drawing: "Rump Roast", undated; 128430 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Drawing: female figure, undated; 128429 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Drawing: guitar player, undated; 128428 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Sketch: reclining figure, undated; 128427 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Sketch: "Honey I'm Home!" b/w severed arm, undated; 128426 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Sketch: seated figure, undated; 128425 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Drawing: diner interior, undated; 128424 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Drawing: "Sam Performing", undated; 128423 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Sketch: "Help! I'm Over-Sexed!", undated; 128422 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Sketch: "Your Christmas Bonus", undated; 128421 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Drawings: license plates and car makes, undated; 128420 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Drawing: "Mikey Writing 'Short Eyes'" [Miguel Pinero], undated; 128419 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Drawing: "Little Mikey Pinero Penitentiary Fox" [Miguel Pinero], undated; 128418 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Drawing: Miguel Pinero, undated; 128417 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Drawing: cat cradled, Jan 22 1985, 128416 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Artwork: "My Trip to America by Martin Wong," ca.1989, 128415 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Drawings: humanoid figures, undated; 128414 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Drawing: "Time" front & back covers, undated; 128413 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Artwork: "Conduct of Ceremonies Handbook", undated; 128412 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Artwork: "Mona Lisa" cover, undated; 128411 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Artwork: "Bible in a Wet Towel"/"Razor in a Toothbrush", undated; 128410 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Sketches: abstract linear pen & ink, undated; 128409 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Sketches: abstract linear pen & ink, undated; 128408 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Sketches: abstract linear, pencil, undated; 128407 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Sketches: abstract linear, other media, undated; 128406 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Sketches: "New Yorker" covers (series), undated; 128405 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Mini-sketchbooks, undated; 128404 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Mini-sketchbooks, undated; 128403 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Mini-sketchbooks, undated; 128402 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Sketches: musicians & musical instruments, undated; 128401 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Sketches: guitar player on horseback, undated; 128400 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Sketch: "Tocci Bros. Daring Escape", undated; 128399 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Sketches: skyscrapers, undated; 128398 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Sketch: graffiti layout, undated; 128397 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Sketches: pistols (series), undated; 128396 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Sketch: "Dental Patient", undated; 128395 (Box 2, Folder 120)